Guide to the Hisham Khatib Collection of photographic prints AD.MC.030
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Hisham Khatib Collection - Prints
1880s - 1930s
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
AD.MC.030
1,573 Photographic Prints Digital surrogates of photographic prints and postcards.
Dr. Hisham Khatib was a Palestinian-Jordanian politician, intellectual and economist. The Hisham Khatib Collection on Palestine and the region once part the Ottoman Empire, including Egypt, Jordan, Syria and Iraq, contains over 4,000 images and was built over 40 years. The majority of objects are 19th century albumen photographic prints, travel albums of the same period and early 20th century, and postcards. There are many images taken by prominent photographers and studios, including; Felix Bonfils, the American Colony, Hippolyte Arnoux, Abdullah Freres, Lehnert and Landrock, Zangaki Brothers and Frances Frith. The photographic portion of the collection (digitized and digitally archived by Akkasah)is part of a larger private collection of maps, paintings and manuscripts.
E-records Digital surrogates only - physical objects not deposited
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Collection obtained directly from Dr. Hisham Khatib and digitized by Akkasah in Amman, Jordan in 2017.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor. The collection was digitized as access was given and arranged according to container and album from Dr. Hisham Khatib's library.
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Hisham Khatib was a Palestinian-Jordanian politician, intellectual and economist of renowned international reputation and a consultant to many local (Jordanian) and international organizations. He was born in Akka (Acre), Palestine in 1937 and lived in Jerusalem until 1974, when he relocated to Jordan.
Dr. Hisham held numerous posts in many Jordanian cabinets. He was Minister of Energy, Water, and Planning. His last posts were as the Head of the Management Committee of the Arab Thought Forum, Honorary Vice Chairman of the World Energy Council and member of many international and regional committees on energy, environment and technology, including the UN Commission on Science and Technology, World Federation of Scientists and Arab East Studies Association. He was decorated in Jordan, Indonesia, Italy, Austria, Sweden and the Vatican. He was also an honorary member of Darat al Funun's advisory board.
Dr. Hisham spent over 40 years building a vast and historically valuable collection of representations of the Near East, focused on the Holy Lands, Palestine, Jordan, Turkey, Syria and Egypt. The artworks in this extensive collection include paintings, lithographic prints, maps, books, photographs and postcards.
He published two books focussed on his collection: Palestine and Egypt Under the Ottomans: Paintings, Books, Photographs, Maps and Manuscripts (2003) and Jerusalem, Palestine and Jordan: In the Archives of Hisham Khatib (2013). He also published Economic Evaluation of Projects in the Electricity Supply Industry - Energy Engineering (2014).
Dr. Hisham Khatib died in June 2022. [Text edited from https://daratalfunun.org]
Scope and Contents
Dr. Hisham Khatib's collection was built over decades from a variety of auctions, rare book dealers and markets. The photographic portion of the collection (digitized and digitally archived by Akkasah) is composed of 2,534 photographic prints (both albumen and gelatin silver) and 1,629 postcards. The main focus is Palestine and the Holy Lands. The collection extends geographically to the wider region under the Ottoman Empire and has a secondary focus on Egypt and a tertiary focus on Syria, Lebanon and Iraq. There are a small number of images (under 10 per country) representing Morocco, Tunisia, Algeria, India, Turkey and Yemen.
A great many images are of archaeological and holy sites in Palestine, in particular the Dome of the Rock [Qubbat Al-Sakhrah] and Al-Aqsa Mosque, the Church Of The Holy Sepulchre and Church of the Nativity as well as other significant mosques and mausoleums in Palestine, Syria and Egypt. There is also a focus on landscapes and to a lesser extent, some images that include people, though very few of these are portraits and many are in the Orientalist tradition of including locals for scale or demonstrations of customs or regional costume.
There are many images taken by prominent photographers/studios, including; Felix Bonfils, the American Colony, Hippolyte Arnoux, Abdullah Freres, Lehnert and Landrock, Zangaki Brothers and Frances Frith.
There are 16 photograph albums, the majority of which were put together by British people who had been on pilgrimages or tours of the Holy Lands or stationed in Palestine, Egypt or Iraq during the Second World War. Of note are the albums created by Les Wells (L. Wells) a serviceman in the British military as two further albums are available in the collections owned by Akkasah: https://specialcollections.library.nyu.edu/search/?utf8=%E2%9C%93&f%5Bformat_sim%5D%5B%5D=Archival+Collection&f%5Brepository_sim%5D%5B%5D=akkasah&per_page=50&q=L.+Wells. Within the postcard collection, the Shlomo Narinsky (Neroni) and Sonia Narinsky album is a rare collection.
All finding aids can be viewed at: https://specialcollections.library.nyu.edu/search/?utf8=%E2%9C%93&f%5Bformat_sim%5D%5B%5D=Archival+Collection&f%5Brepository_sim%5D%5B%5D=akkasah&per_page=50&q=Hisham+Khatib" show="new" actuate="onrequest">.
Egypt; Palestine; Group Portraits; Individual Portraits; Architecture; Iraq; Syria; Religious Sites; Landscapes; Albumen Prints; Postcards; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Travel
- Palestine - Bonfils, Zangaki, L. Fiorillo (Object AD_MC_030_ref148)
  - 1016 - Maison de Simon le corroyeur a Jaffa (House of Simon the tanner in Jaffa). 26.7 x 35.3 cm, Circa 1867-1880; Bonfils, Felix (Object AD_MC_030_ref1)
    Albumen Prints; Buildings; Houses; Jaffa; Men; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Regional/National Dress; Facial Hair; Group Portraits; Turbans
  - 1041 - Mount Zion et Mount de Olives de la Route de Bethlehem (Mount Zion and the Mount of Olives from the road to Bethlehem). 26.7 x 35.3 cm, Circa 1867-1880; Bonfils, Felix (Object AD_MC_030_ref2)
    Albumen Prints; Animals; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Bethlehem; Buildings; French Writing; Goats; Houses; Jerusalem; Landscapes; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites
  - 1117 - Bethlehem, Interieur de la grotte de la Nativité (Church of the Nativity). 26.7 x 35.3 cm, Circa 1870-1890 (Object AD_MC_030_ref3)
    Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Bethlehem; Buildings; Church of the Nativity; Churches; French Writing; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites
  - Interior of the Church of the Holy Sepulchre. 35.3 x 26.7 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_030_ref4)
    Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Churches; Jerusalem; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites
  - 270 - XII et XIII stations le Calvaire, autel grec (the Calvary, Greek altar). 35 x 26.9 cm, Circa 1867-1880; Bonfils, Felix (Object AD_MC_030_ref5)
    Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Churches; French Writing; Jerusalem; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Statues/Sculptures
  - 274 - Jerusalem - Couples du Saint Sepulchre (Domes of the Holy Sepulchre). 26.7 x 35.3 cm, Circa 1867-1880; Bonfils, Felix (Object AD_MC_030_ref6)
    Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Buildings; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Churches; French Writing; Jerusalem; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites
  - 275 - Porte Dorée exterieur, Jerusalem (The Golden Gate). 35.3 x 26.7 cm, Circa 1867-1880; Bonfils, Felix (Object AD_MC_030_ref7)
    Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Buildings; Cemeteries; French Writing; Jerusalem; Men; Palestine; Photographic Prints
  - 240 - Fontaine de Ain Abou Nabout à Jaffa (Sabil Abu Nabbut/ Tabitha's Well). 35.3 x 26.7 cm, Circa 1867-1880; Bonfils, Felix (Object AD_MC_030_ref8)
    Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Buildings; Fountains; French Writing; Jaffa; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Fountains
  - 236 - Jaffa, la passe (The port of Jaffa). 26.9 x 35.3 cm, Circa 1867-1880; Bonfils, Felix (Object AD_MC_030_ref9)
    Albumen Prints; Architecture; Boats/Ships; Buildings; French Writing; Houses; Jaffa; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Ports; Landscapes
  - 346 - Vue générale de Béthanie (A general view of Bethany/Al-Eizariya). 26.8 x 35.4 cm, Circa 1867-1880; Bonfils, Felix (Object AD_MC_030_ref10)
    Al-Eizariya/Bethany; Albumen Prints; Architecture; Buildings; French Writing; Jerusalem; Landscapes; Palestine; Photographic Prints
  - 268 - Couvent Cophte, IXth Station (Coptic Orthodox Patriarchate, 9th Station). 35.5 x 27 cm, Circa 1867-1880; Bonfils, Felix (Object AD_MC_030_ref11)
    Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Religious Crosses; French Writing; Jerusalem; Men; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites
  - 278 - Vue générale de la mosquée d'Omar (Dome of the Rock). 26.9 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1867-1880; Bonfils, Felix (Object AD_MC_030_ref12)
    Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Buildings; Dome of the Rock/Qubbat al-Sakhrah; French Writing; Jerusalem; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf
  - 271 bis - Interieur du St. Sépulcre, le Tombeau (The Tomb at the Holy Sepulchre). 35.5 x 26.7 cm, Circa 1867-1880; Bonfils, Felix (Object AD_MC_030_ref13)
    Albumen Prints; Architecture; Buildings; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Churches; French Writing; Jerusalem; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Tombs/Mausoleums
  - 1081 - XIIe at XIIIe Station le Calvaire autel de Greco (XIIth and XIIIth Stations of Cavalry, the Greek altar). 35.2 x 26.7 cm, Circa 1870-1890 (Object AD_MC_030_ref14)
    Albumen Prints; Architecture; Buildings; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Churches; French Writing; Jerusalem; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites
  - 273 - Jerusalem, Mosquee d'Omar, interieur (Dome of the Rock interior). 26.7 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1867-1880; Bonfils, Felix (Object AD_MC_030_ref15)
  - 855 - Chapelle de Sainte - Helene dans la basilique du St Sépulcre (Chapel of Saint Helena in the Basilica of the Holy Sepulchre). 26.8 x 35.4 cm, Circa 1867-1880; Bonfils, Felix (Object AD_MC_030_ref16)
    Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Churches; French Writing; Jerusalem; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites
  - 853 - Cathedrale Grecque dans la basilique du Saint Sépulcre (Greek Orthodox oratory and chapel in the Church of the Holy Sepulchre). 26.9 x 35.4 cm, Circa 1867-1880; Bonfils, Felix (Object AD_MC_030_ref17)
    Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Churches; French Writing; Jerusalem; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Orthodox Christianity
  - Pierre de l'onction (The Stone of Anointing in the Church of the Holy Sepulchre). 26.7 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1870-1890 (Object AD_MC_030_ref18)
  - 165 - Mont des Oliviers et Église Russe (Mount of Olives and the Russian Orthodox Church of Mary Magdalene). 26.8 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1870-1898 (Object AD_MC_030_ref19)
    Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Churches; French Writing; Jerusalem; Landscapes; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Mount of Olives/Jabal al-Zaytun, Jerusalem; Church of Mary Magdalene, Jerusalem; Religious Sites
  - 1086 - Facade of the Church of the Holy Sepulchre (Saint Sépulcre façade). 35.5 x 26.7 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_030_ref20)
    Albumen Prints; Architecture; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Churches; French Writing; Jerusalem; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites
  - 265 - Jerusalem, Maison de St, Veronique, VI station (The house of Veronica, Via Dolorosa, VIth station). 35.5 x 26.7 cm, Circa 1867-1880; Bonfils, Felix (Object AD_MC_030_ref21)
    Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Buildings; French Writing; Jerusalem; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites
  - 1044 - Khan el-Ahmar sur la route de Jéricho (Khan al-Ahmar, on the road to Jericho). 26.9 x 35.4 cm, Circa 1867-1880; Bonfils, Felix (Object AD_MC_030_ref22)
    Albumen Prints; Animals; Architecture; Buildings; Donkeys; French Writing; Horses; Houses; Jerusalem; Landscapes; Palestine; Photographic Prints; West Bank
  - 937 - Fontaine de la Vierge à Nazareth (The spring of the Virgin Mary/ Mary's Well in Nazareth). 26.7 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1867-1880; Bonfils, Felix (Object AD_MC_030_ref23)
    Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Fountains; French Writing; Nazareth; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Fountains; Springs; Water; Women
  - 367 - Palestine - Mount Carmel. 26.7 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1867-1880; Bonfils, Felix (Object AD_MC_030_ref24)
    Albumen Prints; Animals; Architecture; Buildings; Donkeys; French Writing; Haifa; Landscapes; Men; Mount Carmel /Al-Karmil; Mountains/Hills; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Regional/National Dress; Facial Hair; Canes/Walking Sticks
  - 1040 - Rue de I'Eglise St. Anne a Jerusalem (The street of the Church of Saint Anne, (Via Dolorosa) Jerusalem). 26.8 x 35.4 cm, Circa 1867-1880; Bonfils, Felix (Object AD_MC_030_ref25)
    Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Buildings; Children; Churches; French Writing; Jerusalem; Men; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Streets/Roads; Regional/National Dress; Women; Religious Sites; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Turbans
  - 1032 - Panorama de Jerusalem. 26.8 x 35.5 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_030_ref26)
    Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Buildings; French Writing; Jerusalem; Landscapes; Palestine; Photographic Prints
  - 287 - Porte de Damas a Jérusalem (The Damascus Gate in Jerusalem). 26.7 x 35.5 cm, Undated; Bonfils, Felix (Object AD_MC_030_ref27)
    Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Buildings; French Writing; Jerusalem; Men; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Women
- Palestine, Sinai and Turkey - Frank Mason Good and Frances Frith (Object AD_MC_030_ref149)
  - 525 -The Written Valley, Sinai (Wadi Mukattab). 27.8 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1857-1860 (Object AD_MC_030_ref28)
    Albumen Prints; Egypt; English Writing; Landscapes; Men; Mountains/Hills; New Church Theological School; Photographic Prints; Sinai, Egypt; Regional/National Dress
  - 527 - Rephidim, Paran (Wady Feiran, Sinai). 27.8 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1865 (Object AD_MC_030_ref29)
    Albumen Prints; Egypt; English Writing; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; New Church Theological School; Outdoors; Palm Trees; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Rivers; Sinai, Egypt
  - 537 - Hazeroth (Huderah). 27.8 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1857-1870 (Object AD_MC_030_ref30)
    Albumen Prints; Egypt; English Writing; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; New Church Theological School; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Sinai, Egypt
  - 595 - Nazareth from the West, with the distant Summit of Tabor. 27.9 x 35.4 cm, Circa 1857-1870 (Object AD_MC_030_ref31)
    Albumen Prints; Architecture; Buildings; English Writing; Landscapes; Nazareth; New Church Theological School; Palestine; Photographic Prints
  - 606 - Mount Hermon, Mount of Transfiguration. 28 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1857-1870 (Object AD_MC_030_ref32)
    Albumen Prints; English Writing; Landscapes; Lebanon; Mountains/Hills; New Church Theological School; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Snow; Syria
  - Magdala, or Migdel, on the Sea of Galilee; the only inhabited spot in the Plain of Gennesaret. 27.8 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1857-1870 (Object AD_MC_030_ref33)
    Albumen Prints; Buildings; English Writing; Galilee; Landscapes; New Church Theological School; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Tiberias/Tabariyyah
  - 465 - Mount Tabor. 27.8 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1857-1870 (Object AD_MC_030_ref34)
    Albumen Prints; English Writing; Galilee; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; New Church Theological School; Palestine; Photographic Prints
  - 468 - Mount Tabor. 27.8 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1857-1870 (Object AD_MC_030_ref35)
  - Mount Hermon from the west. 27.8 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1857-1870 (Object AD_MC_030_ref36)
    Albumen Prints; English Writing; Landscapes; Lebanon; Mountains/Hills; New Church Theological School; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Syria
  - Naplouse: le Grand-Prêtre des Samaritains (Nablus: the High Priest of the Samaritans). 41.6 x 30.3 cm, Circa 1857-1870 (Object AD_MC_030_ref37)
    Albumen Prints; Aramaic Writing; French Writing; Individual Portraits; Men; New Church Theological School; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Priests/Clergymen; Regional/National Dress; Priests/Clergymen; Samaritans; Torah; Turbans; Facial Hair; Lanterns/Lamps; Chandeliers
  - 1724 - Constantinople, Mosque of Sulieman and Golden Horn. 27.8 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1857-1870 (Object AD_MC_030_ref38)
    Albumen Prints; Architecture; Bosphorus; Buildings; Constantinople; English Writing; Istanbul, Turkey; Mosques; New Church Theological School; Photographic Prints; Suleymaniye Mosque; The Golden Horn/Haliç; Turkey; Religious Sites
  - 617 - Smyrna (Izmir). 27.8 x 35.5 cm, Undated (Object AD_MC_030_ref39)
    Aegean Sea; Albumen Prints; Architecture; Boats/Ships; Buildings; English Writing; Izmir, Turkey; New Church Theological School; Photographic Prints; Seas; Smyrna; Turkey; Landscapes
  - View of Djenin (Jenin), the ancient En-Gannim, showing the Mountains of Gilboa in the distance. 27.8 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1857-1870 (Object AD_MC_030_ref40)
    Albumen Prints; Buildings; Cemeteries; English Writing; Houses; Jenin; Landscapes; New Church Theological School; Palestine; Palm Trees; Photographic Prints; Tombs/Mausoleums; West Bank; Religious Sites
  - Fishing boat, Lake of Gennesaret (Sea of Galilee). 27.8 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1857-1870 (Object AD_MC_030_ref41)
    Albumen Prints; Boats/Ships; English Writing; Fishing; Galilee; Lakes; Men; New Church Theological School; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Sea of Galilee/Lake Tiberias; Seas; Landscapes
  - Central Palestine, Shiloh (Seilun). 27.8 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1857-1870 (Object AD_MC_030_ref42)
    Albumen Prints; English Writing; Landscapes; Men; Mountains/Hills; New Church Theological School; Outdoors; Palestine; Photographic Prints; West Bank
  - Sebaste, the site of Samaria. 28.2 x 35.7 cm, Circa 1857-1870 (Object AD_MC_030_ref43)
    Albumen Prints; English Writing; Landscapes; Nablus; New Church Theological School; Outdoors; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Samaria/as-Sāmirah; West Bank
  - Pine tree, Jerusalem. 27.8 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1857-1870 (Object AD_MC_030_ref44)
    Albumen Prints; Buildings; English Writing; Jerusalem; New Church Theological School; Outdoors; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Landscapes
  - Thorn tree, Jordan Valley, southern Palestine. 27.8 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1857-1870 (Object AD_MC_030_ref45)
    Albumen Prints; English Writing; Landscapes; Men; New Church Theological School; Outdoors; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Regional/National Dress; Facial Hair; Guns; Weapons; Group Portraits
  - Ruins of synagogue at Tell Hum (Capernaum). 27.8 x 35.5 cm, Circa 1857-1870 (Object AD_MC_030_ref46)
    Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; English Writing; Galilee; New Church Theological School; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Synagogues
- Palestine and Trans-Jordan - Frank Mason Good, Bonfils, American Colony, J.Bendov et al (Object AD_MC_030_ref150)
  - 371 - Fourteenth Station. The Tomb. XIV Station, Heiliges Grab. 27.3 x 21.2 cm, Circa 1898-1914 (Object AD_MC_030_ref48)
    Albumen Prints; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Churches; English Writing; German Writing; Jerusalem; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Tombs/Mausoleums
  - 343 - The Holy Sepulchre. Grabeskapelle. Saint Sepulcre. 27.3 x 21.2 cm, Circa 1898-1914 (Object AD_MC_030_ref49)
    Albumen Prints; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Churches; English Writing; French Writing; German Writing; Jerusalem; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites
  - 370 - XII and XIII. Station Calvary. XII and XIII Station Golgotha. XII et XIII Station. 21.5 x 27.8 cm, Circa 1898-1914 (Object AD_MC_030_ref50)
    Albumen Prints; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Churches; English Writing; French Writing; German Writing; Head Covers/Veils; Jerusalem; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Women
  - 345 - Greek Cathedral. Griechische Kapelle. Cathedrale Greque. 21.4 x 27.7 cm, Circa 1898-1914 (Object AD_MC_030_ref51)
  - 337 - Church of the Sepulchre. Grabeskirche. Eglise du Sepulcre. 27.5 x 21.2 cm, Circa 1898-1914 (Object AD_MC_030_ref52)
    Albumen Prints; Architecture; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Churches; English Writing; French Writing; German Writing; Jerusalem; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites
  - 342 - The Holy Sepulchre. Grabeskapelle. Saint Sepulcre. 27.5 x 21.4 cm, Circa 1898-1914 (Object AD_MC_030_ref53)
  - 355 - A Street in Jerusalem. Strasse in Jerusalem. Une Rue de Jerusalem. 27.5 x 21.2 cm, Circa 1898-1914 (Object AD_MC_030_ref54)
    Albumen Prints; Architecture; English Writing; French Writing; German Writing; Jerusalem; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Streets/Roads
  - 336 - Steps leading to the Holy Sepulchre. Les marches qui conduisent au St. Sepulcre. 27.5 x 20.9 cm, Circa 1898-1914 (Object AD_MC_030_ref55)
    Albumen Prints; Architecture; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Crowds; English Writing; French Writing; Jerusalem; Men; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Women; Streets/Roads; Street Lamps; Hats; Regional/National Dress; Turbans; Fez/Tarboush; Boys; Children; Churches
  - 401 - St. Stephen's Gate. Stephans Thor. porte de St. Etienne. 28 x 21.5 cm, Circa 1898-1914 (Object AD_MC_030_ref57)
    Albumen Prints; Animals; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; English Writing; French Writing; German Writing; Horses; Jerusalem; Lions' Gate; Men; Palestine; Photographic Prints
  - 402 - Gate of Christ's Triumphal Entry. Goldenes Thor. Porte Doree. 21 x 27.7 cm, Circa 1898-1914 (Object AD_MC_030_ref58)
    Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Cemeteries; English Writing; French Writing; German Writing; Golden Gate, Jerusalem; Jerusalem; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites
  - 303 - Through the Rocks Jaffa. Celfen vor Jaffa. A travers la Passe. 21.3 x 27.8 cm, Circa 1898-1914 (Object AD_MC_030_ref59)
    Albumen Prints; Boats/Ships; Coast; English Writing; French Writing; German Writing; Jaffa; Mediterranean Sea; Men; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Seas; Landscapes
  - 318 - Citadel of Zion. Zitadelle. Citadelle de Sion (Tower of David/Jerusalem Citadel) 21.3 x 27.8 cm, Circa 1898-1914 (Object AD_MC_030_ref60)
    Albumen Prints; Animals; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Carriages/Coaches; Horses; Jerusalem; Mount Zion/Jabal Sahyoun, Jerusalem; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Tower of David/Burj Dāwūd (Jerusalem Citadel); Forts/Castles
  - 321 - Jaffa Gate. Jaffa Thor. Porte de Jaffa. 27.5 x 21.2 cm, Circa 1898-1914 (Object AD_MC_030_ref61)
    Albumen Prints; Animals; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Buildings; Carriages/Coaches; English Writing; French Writing; German Writing; Horses; Jerusalem; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Clocks/Watches
  - 391 - Damascus Gate. Damascus thor. Porte de Damas. 21.3 x 27.8 cm, Circa 1898-1914 (Object AD_MC_030_ref62)